const data = [
  {
    category: "Red Blood Cells",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What shape do sickle cells take?",
        options: ["Drepanocyte", "Round shape", "Teardrop shape", "Oval shape"],
        answer: "Drepanocyte",
      },
      {
        question: "What condition features teardrop-shaped red blood cells?",
        options: ["Dacryocyte", "Elliptocyte", "Sickle cell", "Spherocyte"],
        answer: "Dacryocyte",
      },
      {
        question: "What abnormality involves oval-shaped red blood cells?",
        options: [
          "Elliptocytes",
          "Dacryocytes",
          "Sickle cells",
          "Schistocytes",
        ],
        answer: "Elliptocytes",
      },
      {
        question: "What is a primary characteristic of polycythemia vera?",
        options: [
          "Decreased white blood cell count",
          "Elevated platelet count",
          "Overproduction of red blood cells",
          "Deficiency in clotting factors",
        ],
        answer: "Elevated platelet count",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What general term describes a deficiency in red blood cells or hemoglobin?",
        options: ["Anemia", "Polycythemia", "Leukopenia", "Thrombocytopenia"],
        answer: "Anemia",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    category: "White Blood Cells",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What characterizes acute leukemia with blasts?",
        options: [
          "High number of immature white blood cells",
          "High number of mature lymphocytes",
          "Predominance of promyelocytes",
          "Decreased red blood cells",
        ],
        answer: "High number of immature white blood cells",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which cell is common in hematological cancer Multiple Myeloma?",
        options: ["Plasmocytes", "Lymphocytes", "Promyelocytes", "Blast"],
        answer: "Plasmocytes",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does a left shift with myelocytes to promyelocytes indicate?",
        options: [
          "Acute leukemia",
          "Chronic leukemia",
          "Severe infection",
          "Mild anemia",
        ],
        answer: "Severe infection",
      },
      {
        question: "What is a characteristic of myelodysplastic syndrome?",
        options: [
          "Abnormal and ineffective blood cell production",
          "Excessive production of red blood cells",
          "High number of mature lymphocytes",
          "Decreased levels of hemoglobin",
        ],
        answer: "Abnormal and ineffective blood cell production",
      },
      {
        question: "What is commonly seen in sepsis infection?",
        options: [
          "Increased number of neutrophils",
          "Decreased number of neutrophils",
          "Increased number of lymphocytes",
          "Decreased number of lymphocytes",
        ],
        answer: "Increased number of neutrophils",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "Platelets",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the primary function of platelets?",
        options: [
          "Transport oxygen",
          "Fight infections",
          "Form blood clots",
          "Regulate blood pressure",
        ],
        answer: "Form blood clots",
      },
      {
        question: "What is a condition characterized by low platelet count?",
        options: ["Thrombocytopenia", "Leukopenia", "Anemia", "Polycythemia"],
        answer: "Thrombocytopenia",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following can cause an increase in platelet count?",
        options: [
          "Iron deficiency anemia",
          "Viral infection",
          "Vitamin D deficiency",
          "Bacterial infection",
        ],
        answer: "Iron deficiency anemia",
      },
    ],
  },
];
export default data;
